# **Brian Duffield**

Toronto, Ontario

brianduffield@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/brianduffieldtoronto brianduffield.github.io

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Highly experienced and versatile IT professional specializing in technical documentation with a keen focus on product development. More than 15 years of experience as a professional writer and manager, working in the Enterprise and Cloud software industry. Proven ability to create accurate documentation for highly technical audiences as well as general software users. Demonstrated talent for working on multiple projects, with multiple stakeholders, under demanding deadlines. Thoroughly familiar with Agile software development environment and documentation's role within it.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Product Documentation and Training Manager**

Tier1 Financial Solutions Oct 2018 - Apr 2020

 Led team of 4 writers to support existing and new products built on Salesforce CRM. Delivered user guides, release notes, and configuration documentation for all releases.

### **Senior Product and Documentation Specialist**

Tier1 Financial Solutions Jan 2017 - Oct 2018

• Developed User Guides, OLH, and Release documentation for multiple CRM products.

#### **Product and Documentation Specialist**

Pulse Systems, Canada Feb 2016 - Oct 2018

 Developed User Guides, OLH, and Release documentation for multiple eHR products.

#### **Documentation Manager**

Oracle, Canada Mar 2006 - June 2015

 Managed multiple documentation teams within Oracle focused on developer and platform documentation. Content included installation, development, customization, server admin, tools, security, APIs, and mobile frameworks.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS AND EXPERTISE

Extensive experience with technical communication industry, practices, and innovations, such as DITA, data-chunking, task-based design, minimalism, content strategy, and UX/UI integrations.

Over five years of experience using Agile methodology, including writing user stories and participating in team scrums, planning, pointing, grooming, and retros.

Consistent focus on user-centered documentation: understanding the documentation audience and delivering content – in the ideal formats – to ensure client success.

Tool experience with MadCap Flare, Adobe Structured FrameMaker, Markdown language, and editors such as Atom; experience with Confluence, wikis, JIRA, Slack, and Rally; knowledge of sourcecontrol systems SVN, GIT, and SDL.

Thorough understanding of web application design using HTML, HTML5, XML, CSS, and JavaScript; programming experience with PHP and other languages; database expertise with MySQL.

- Co-author of ARMA (American Record Management Association) technical report on mobile communications and security (Mobile Communications and Records and Information Management -ARMA TR-20-2012 – ISBN ISBN: 978-1-936654-08-6, published in 2012).
- LinkedIn Article: <u>Help When You Need It</u>.
- Published in National Post, Globe and Mail, Society of Technical Communications (STC) Intercom Magazine, and other publications.

#### **EDUCATION**

- Computer Science Certificate Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario
- Bachelor of Engineering (Civil) Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario
- Bachelor of Science (Mathematics) Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia